# SHAIK UZMA NOOR

#### 7842378365

# shaikuzmanoor@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/shaik-uzma-noor-95432287/

#### **SUMMARY OF EXPERIENCE**

Around 4 years of experience in Full stack development. Having sound knowledge of both backend and frontend development.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Skills : Java, REST, Data Structures, C, C++, SQL, GIT

Web Technologies : HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Ajax, NodeJs, npm, ExpressJs,

ReactJs, AngularJs, KnockoutJs, OJET, Wijmo, Bootstrap.

Frameworks : Spring (basic), Selenium

Databases : SQL Server, MongoDB

Big Data Analytics Tools: Cloudera Manager CDH

Big Data Technologies : Hadoop

Tools : Eclipse, IntelliJ IDEA, Visual Studio, Atom, Postman, SoapUI

Application Servers : Tomcat, Jenkins

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **DEC 2019 - PRESENT**

#### **ORACLE, APPLICATIONS ENGINEER**

Technologies: Java, REST API, Knockout JS, OJET, VBCS and Oracle SQL databases

- Working with Oracle Application Labs (OAL) in CRM Internal Projects.
- Responsible for designing, developing and deploying custom apps to be used by the
  Oracle sales team. Developed various dashboards in CRM Applications.

### **Notable projects:**

#### **Opportunity Management System:**

- Built a custom tool where sales personnel can create Opportunities based on the sales leads.
- Have designed and developed flows for sales admins where they can cancel and extend

cloud renewals.

 Also took initiative for automating all the flows to do functional testing using Selenium and trained many teams to get started with.

### Bulk upload tool:

- It's an extensible system that facilitates the Opportunity/Lead objects to be created in bulk when an Organization is acquired by Oracle.
- Have designed this application which reduced the time taken for Opportunities/Leads to be created by 75%.

#### **JULY 2017 - DEC 2019**

# NCR CORPORATION, SOFTWARE ENGINEER (APR 2018 – DEC 2019), ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER (JUL 2017 – MAR 2018)

**Technologies:** Java, Servlets, JSP, Wijmo, Spring, Web Services, JDBC, PL/SQL, HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery and AJAX, Tomcat.

#### **Worked for Master Data Management**

- Master Data management is a retail application dealing with the data management relating to stores, items assigned to specific stores and their audit data.
- It is a client ready retail application used by US clients like Deca, FSA, Lipari, Meijer.

#### Responsibilities:

- Take full ownership of all the development tasks assigned.
- Design and develop the solutions end to end both backend and frontend side.
- Actively pick-up, analyze and address the production support issues.

#### Features developed:

- The first feature developed gives the flexibility for the user to compare data on the screen to the data present in the database.
- The next feature gives the user the flexibility to create his own grids and allows user to select the columns which he wants to display in the grids.
- Developed a picker which allows the user to create their own syntactically correct queries where the table names are exposed and user gets to format and select the appropriate tables, joins, conditions, etc.

#### **JUN 2016 – JULY 2016**

# **OOMPFH INFO TECH. SOLUTIONS,** SECONDARY RESEARCH AND DEVELOPMENT AS INTERN

Analyzing the market, capture business model and pull out USP's of all competitor companies to create a unique product which is implemented with go-getter strategy as a part of research and

development.

#### **PROJECTS**

#### **REVERSE DICTIONARY**

The main aim of this project is to display the related words when a description or a meaning is given as input.

Technologies : Java, Hadoop.

Tools Used : Cloudera CDH4, Eclipse.

#### **BLOG PROJECT**

This is a blog page where anyone could compose and share their stories anonymously. User can register and update or delete the existing stories. This project is deployed using Heroku.

Technologies : NodeJs, ExpressJs, npm, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, PassportJs.

Database : MongoDB.

Tools Used : Atom.

Link : https://blog-to-cheer.herokuapp.com/

#### **GET VENUES**

The main objective of this project is to list the nearest venue you are looking for in that particular area and give most recent review and sentiment score of that place.

Technologies Used : Angular JS, HTML & CSS

Tools Used : Eclipse and Tomcat

# **EDUCATION**

2017

**CHAITANYA BHARATHI INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, CGPA: 8.09** 

B.E. in Information Technology

2013

NARAYANA JUNIOR COLLEGE, PERCENTAGE: 97.7

BOARD OF INTERMEDIATE, AP.

Board of Intermediate, AP.

2011

ST. JOSEPH'S ENGLISH SCHOOL, CGPA: 10

**CBSE Board** 

## **ACHIEVEMENTS**

- PEGA Certified System Architect.
- Research and Development Internship at OOMPFH info tech solutions.
- Campus Ambassador for 1000 job mela conducted by OOMPFH info tech solutions.
- Presented a paper on 'Map Reduce' in Headstart 2k14 in CBIT.
- Coordinated for Cognos (paper presentation) event in National level Technical symposium Tecstasy 2k15 in CBIT.
- Volunteered for Cognos (paper presentation) event in National level Technical symposium Tecstasy 2k14 in CBIT.
- Certified as an active member of NSS.